MICHAEL ARAO

WEB ARTISAN

+639178083496

Q Taguig Clty, NCR, Philippines

michaelangelo.arao@gmail.com

ABOUT ME

I am well-versed in current front-end web development technologies and have vast knowledge and working experience utilizing HTML5, CSS3, and JS to provide solutions. Most of my projects are done on WordPress, Bootstrap, and Tailwind, but I am inclined to do projects from scratch. I also have experience designing websites and mockups using Figma and SketchApp.

EXPERTISE

HTML5 Gulp (using Node.js)

CSS3 Github
JS, JQuery NPM

PHP Jira, Trello, Slack and other

WordPress major collaboration tools

WebFlow

EDUCATION

STI College BGC

Bachelor of Science in Information Technology

2012

Thesis: JAVA-VLE (Java

Virtual Learning Environment)

EXPERIENCE

Developer

Jun 2020 - Present

500 Designs (USA, Remote)

Code well-designed, testable, efficient solutions using best web development practices and mainly coordinating with designers and clients to deliver the best approach for a specific project.

Lead Web Developer

2017 - 2020

Aura Online (AU, Remote)

I lead the Manila team's Web Development team, I not only delegate tasks and manage projects, but I am also the goto guy for big client projects.

Lead Web Developer

2014 - 2017

Optimal Online Marketing (SG)

I became the External team's lead in my 3rd month in OOm and was the key guy for high-value clients. Aside from coding, I also regularly conduct group learning sessions to improve the team's knowledge, practices, and working relationship.

EXPERIENCE

Developer

2013 - 2014

Variation Media (CA, Remote)

I am the only dev for Variation Media. This is my first time encountering in-depth WordPress development and frontend frameworks like Bootstrap and Foundation. Variation Media is a company based in Ontario, Canada, and I worked as a remote employee.

Freelance Web Developer

2012 - Present

Direct Clients / Upwork

Handles multiple startup and outsourced projects on weekends and long breaks.